$CACOAlchemy	Alchemy
$CACOCooking	Cooking
$CACOHarvest	Harvest
$CACOFarming	Farming
$CACONeeds	Basic Needs
$CACOHelp	Help
$CACO1sec	1 sec
$CACO5secs	10 secs
$CACO10secs	20 secs
$CACOVanilla	Vanilla
$CACODangerous	Dangerous
$CACODeadly	Deadly
$CACOBeginner	BEGINNER
$CACOCook	COOK
$CACOChef	CHEF
$CACOConnoisseur	CONNOISSEUR
$CACOGourmand	GOURMAND	
$CACONone	None
$CACO3rdPerson	3rd Person
$CACO1stPerson	1st Person
$CACOAbundant	Abundant
$CACOReduced	Reduced
$CACOVeryFew	Few
$CACOSingleItem	Single Item
$CACOCommon	Common
$CACOUncommon	Uncommon
$CACOScarce	Scarce
$CACONever	Never
$CACOPlayerOwned	Player Owned
$CACOAll	All
$CACOAfterQuest	After Quest
$CACOAlwaysAllow	Always Allow
$CACODisable	Disable
$CACOGrowingTime	Growing Time
$CACOHarvestAmount	Harvest Amount
$CACOBoth	Both
$CACOPotionDuration	Potion Duration
$CACORestoreHealth	Restore Health
$CACORestoreMagicka	Restore Magicka
$CACORestoreStamina	Restore Stamina
$CACOEffectOptions	Effect Options
$CACONoStacking	Restore Effects Do Not Stack
$CACONoVampireRestore	No Restore Health for Vampires
$CACORecipeOptions	Recipe Options
$CACOLearnRecipes	Learn Effects from Recipes
$CACORetortConditions	Inventory Conditions on Retort Recipes
$CACODistillRecipes	Distill Potion Recipes
$CACOPoisonDuration	Poison Duration
$CACODamageHealth	Damage Health
$CACODamageMagicka	Damage Magicka
$CACODamageStamina	Damage Stamina
$CACOOtherOptions	Other Options
$CACOXPMultiplier	XP Multiplier:
$CACORenamePlayerPotions	Rename Player Potions
$CACORequireMortar	Require Mortar & Pestle to use Alchemy Lab
$CACOBombNotifications	Remaining Bomb Notifications
$CACOLoadScreens	CACO Load Screens
$CACOCookingSkill	Cooking Skill
$CACOEnableCookSkill	Enable Cooking Skill
$CACOCookSkillLevel	Your Cooking Skill Level:
$CACOCookSkillRank	Your Skill Rank:
$CACOXPNotifications	XP Notifications
$CACOAddedCookingRecipes	Added Cooking Recipes
$CACOCookingConditions	Inventory Conditions on Cooking Recipes
$CACOWater	Water
$CACOCraftWater	Craft Water
$CACOWaterFromWells	Get Water from Wells
$CACORequireBucket	Require Bucket
$CACOAlcohol	Alcohol
$CACODrunkenVisuals	Drunken Visual Effects
$CACODrunkenAnimations	Drunken Animations
$CACOInebriationMessages	Enable Inebriation Messages
$CACOToleranceRate	Increased Tolerance Rate
$CACOIngredients	Ingredients
$CACOMinimumIngredients	Minimum Ingredients
$CACOAdjusted	Adjusted
$CACOPrePerkIngrChance	Pre-Perk Ingredient Chance
$CACOPostPerkIngrChance	Post-Perk Ingredient Chance
$CACOFoodContainers	Food Containers
$CACOFrequency	Frequency
$CACOQuantity	Quantity
$CACOCreatures&NPCs	Creatures & NPCs
$CACOMeatAmount	Meat Amount
$CACOMilk&Wool	Milk & Wool
$CACODeadlyVenoms	Deadly Venoms
$CACOHarvestFlesh	Harvest Flesh
$CACOActivationType	Activation Type
$CACOMessageBox	Message Box
$CACOAutomatic	Automatic
$CACOGardening	Gardening
$CACOInitialGrowthTime	Initial Growth Time
$CACODaystoRegrow	Days to Regrow
$CACOFertilizerDuration	Fertilizer Duration
$CACOFertilizerEffect	Fertilizer Effect
$CACOFarmingJobs	Farming Jobs
$CACOCabbages	Cabbages
$CACOSquash	Squash
$CACOLeeks	Leeks
$CACONirnroot	Nirnroot
$CACOPotatoes	Potatoes
$CACOWheat	Wheat
$CACOSleepOptions	Sleep Options
$CACORestrictRested	Restrict Rested Duration
$CACOMinRestedTime	Minimum Time Required for Rested
$CACORestedWerewolves	Rested Bonus for Werewolves
$CACOHunger&Fatigue	Hunger & Fatigue
$CACOHungerPenalties	Enable Hunger Penalties
$CACOFatiguePenalties	Enable Fatigue Penalties
$CACONotificationMessages	Notification Messages
$CACOGeneralCompatibility	General Compatibility
$CACOMarkHarvestedNPCs	Mark Harvested NPCs as Eaten
$CACORecombinePortions	Recombine Portions while Cooking
$CACODisableAlchemyLab	Disable Alchemy Workbench Options
$CACODisableChurn	Disable Butter Churn Changes
$CACODisableItemSwap	Disable Auto Item Swapping
$CACOSwapSoulHusks	Swap Soul Husks
$CACOSwapHorkerTusks	Swap Horker Tusks
$CACOSwapHeartscales	Swap Dragon Heartscales
$CACOSwapHumanFlesh	Swap Human Flesh
$CACOSwapBoneHawkClaws	Swap Bone Hawk Claws
$CACOSwapBoneHawkFeathers	Swap Bone Hawk Feathers
$CACOSwapSkeeverHide	Swap Charred Skeever Hide
$CACOSwapScalpel	Swap Scalpel
$CACOiNeedCompatibility	iNeed Compatibility
$CACOUpdateiNeedLists	Update iNeed Lists
$CACOTroubleshooting	Troubleshooting
$CACOUpdatePotionWeights	Update Potion Weights
$CACORagdollParalysis	Ragdoll Paralysis
$CACOStopDrunkenAnimations	Stop Drunken Animations
$CACOForTesting	For Testing Purposes
$CACOGiveIngredients	Give Ingredients to Player
$CACOLearnAllEffects	Learn All Ingredient Effects
$CACOGiveNewFood	Give New Foods to Player
$CACOGiveNewTools	Give New Tools & Misc Items to Player
$CACOContinue	Continue
$CACOCancel	Cancel
$CACOOkay	Okay
$CACOMsgRevealEffects	WARNING!\nThis will reveal all effects for all ingredients, both new and vanilla.  This action cannot be undone.\n\nDo you want to continue?
$CACOMsgPotionWeight	This will update the weight values assigned to player-made potions.  Please allow a minute or two for this function to complete.
$CACOMsgUpdateiNeed	This will update iNeed's food and drink lists with items from CACO.  Please allow a minute or two for this function to complete.
$CACOMsgCookingSkill_Novice	Cooking Skill: NOVICE\n\nYou can create only the most basic of meals by applying heat to food.  While this is sufficient for simple sustenance, the results are often tough, dry meats and overcooked, mushy vegetables.  However, with determination and practice your cooking skill will increase, and the food you create will become more appetizing.
$CACOMsgCookingSkill_Apprentice	Cooking Skill: APPRENTICE\n\nYou have moved beyond scorching meat and drowning vegetables.  Your attempts at cooking have progressed past basic sustenance, and while the foods you create remain simple and rustic, the addition of seasonings and spices enhance your meals.\n\nYou can now create basic soups, advanced stews and bake simple breads and basic sweets.
$CACOMsgCookingSkill_Adept	Cooking Skill: ADEPT\n\nA new confidence is apparent in your cooking, and while simple wholesome dishes are great for everyday meals, you start to experiment with adding a bit more flare to your dishes.  Unusual ingredients can contribute interesting flavor profiles and add a new twist to old standbys.\n\nYou can now braise and pickle meats, prepare sausages and create advanced soups and stews.  Sweet and savoury pies can be baked in ovens.
$CACOMsgCookingSkill_Expert	Cooking Skill: EXPERT\n\nYou are becoming a true master of the flame and kettle.  Flair and panache are evident in the meals you create.  Your vegetables are a perfect balance of crisp and tender, and you can make even the toughest cut of meat melt like butter on the tongue.\n\nYou can now create complex and fancy sweet and savoury dishes and know how to use rare and unusual ingredients in your cooking.
$CACOMsgCookingSkill_Master	Cooking Skill: MASTER\n\nYour hard work has gained you a mastery of food that few can match.  Your meals are a masterpiece worthy of a true gourmand, and only the tables of kings and the banquet halls of Sovengard can match the quality of your fare.
$CACODesc_IngrPrePerkChance	Percent chance of harvesting additional ingredients from plants, mushrooms, and other flora prior to taking the Naturalist perk.  Default: 30%
$CACODesc_IngrPostPerkChance	Percent chance of harvesting additional ingredients from plants, mushrooms, and other flora after taking the Naturalist perk.  Default: 60%
$CACODesc_MinIngredients	This mod adjusts the minimum number of harvestable ingredients for certain plants.  This means that for certain items, like wheat and mountain berries, you will always receive more than one ingredient per harvest.  If you wish to use the vanilla minimum of one ingredient per harvest then select 'Vanilla' for this option.
$CACODesc_MinMeat	This mod adjusts the amount of meat acquired from certain animals.  If you wish to use the vanilla amount of one meat or food item per animal then select 'Vanilla' for this option.
$CACODesc_GardenInitialTime	The number of days between planting an item and the first harvest.
$CACODesc_GardenRegrowTime	The number of days it takes for planted items to regrow and be ready to harvest again.
$CACODesc_GardenFertilizerTime	The number of days that soil will remain fertile after applying fertilizer.
$CACODesc_GardenFertilizerOpt	Choose what effect fertilizer will have on the soil:\n1)Applications of fertilizer will progressively enrich the soil, slowly reducing both the Initial Growth Time and the Regrowth Time for up to a maximum of 35% faster plant growth.\n2)An application of fertilizer will increase the amount you harvest from the plant.\n3)Receive both effects.
$CACODesc_FarmJobCabbage	The number of cabbages needed to earn 1 gold from farmers.
$CACODesc_FarmJobGourd	The number of squash needed to earn 1 gold from farmers.
$CACODesc_FarmJobLeek	The number of leeks needed to earn 1 gold from farmers.
$CACODesc_FarmJobNirnroot	The number of nirnroots needed to earn 1 gold from farmers.
$CACODesc_FarmJobPotato	The number of potatoes needed to earn 1 gold from farmers.
$CACODesc_FarmJobWheat	The number of wheat needed to earn 1 gold from farmers.
$CACODesc_AddIngredient	Adds 10 of every ingredient to the Player's inventory.
$CACODesc_AddFood	Adds every new food item to the Player's inventory.
$CACODesc_AddTools	Adds new alchemy tools, bombs, bandages, and other new items to the Player's inventory.
$CACODesc_LearnEffects	Reveals all effects for every ingredient in the game.
$CACODesc_SwapItems	This mod automatically exchanges certain vanilla items for their CACO equivalents when added to the player's inventory.  Deselecting this option will disable the automatic conversion and allow for manual conversion between CACO and vanilla items.  This may be necessary if you are using other mods that require the vanilla items, use them for crafting, etc.
$CACODesc_SwapSoulHusk	Swaps all Soul Husks in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_SwapHorkerTusk	Swaps all Horker Tusks in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_SwapDragonScales	Swaps all Dragon Heartscales in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_SwapHumanFlesh	Swaps all Human Flesh in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_SwapSkeeverHide	Swaps all Charred Skeever Hide in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the ingredient and food versions of Charred Skeever Hide.  By default, CACO will automatically convert the ingredient version of Charred Skeever Hide into the food version of this item.
$CACODesc_SwapBoneHawkClaw	Swaps all Bone Hawk Claws in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_SwapBoneHawkFeather	Swaps all Bone Hawk Feathers in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_SwapScalpel	Swaps all Scalpels in the Player's inventory.  This allows for conversion between the vanilla items and CACO items if using another mod that requires use of the vanilla items.
$CACODesc_HealthDur	Adjusts the duration for Restore Health potions. Potion magnitudes will be also adjusted according to the duration selected.
$CACODesc_StaminaDur	Adjusts the duration for Restore Stamina potions.  Potion magnitudes will be also adjusted according to the duration selected.
$CACODesc_MagickaDur	Adjusts the duration for Restore Magicka potions.  Potion magnitudes will be also adjusted according to the duration selected.
$CACODesc_HealthDamDur	Adjusts the duration for Damage Health potions.  Potion magnitudes will be also adjusted according to the duration selected.
$CACODesc_StaminaDamDur	Adjusts the duration for Damage Stamina potions.  Potion magnitudes will be also adjusted according to the duration selected.
$CACODesc_MagickaDamDur	Adjusts the duration for Damage Magicka potions.  Potion magnitudes will be also adjusted according to the duration selected.
$CACODesc_VampireRestoreHealth	If selected, regular Restore Health, Fortify Health, and Health Regeneration potions won't have any effect on vampires.  Instead, vampires will need to rely on Potions of Blood or other means of restoring health.
$CACODesc_StackableEffects	If selected, Restore Health, Stamina, and Magicka potions will not stack with other potions using the same effect.  For example, if two Restore Health potions are taken at the same time, the one with the lower magnitude will be dispelled automatically.
$CACODesc_RequireMortar	If selected, then you will be required to have a mortar and pestle in your inventory in order to use the Alchemy Lab.
$CACODesc_RenamePotions	If selected, the all potions and poisons created by the player will be named in a manner consistent with the generic potions, reflecting both the potion's type and quality.  However, these renamed potions do not stack with other identical potions until a reload.  Changes to this setting will only affect newly created potions.  Existing potions will retain the names they were given at the time they were created.
$CACODesc_FoodFrequency	This setting controls how often barrels and sacks will contain food.
$CACODesc_FoodQuantity	This setting controls the amount of food found in barrels and sacks.  It will also reduce the food quantities available at certain merchants.
$CACODesc_DeadlyVenom	Increases the poison damage inflicted by venomous creatures such as spiders and chaurus.\nBites will deliver strong, shorter duration effects.  Spit attacks will deliver less intense damage for a much longer duration.
$CACODesc_MilkWool	Allows you to acquire milk from cows once a day and wool from sheep* once a week.  You can choose to limit this feature to only player-owned animals, apply it to all living, non-hostile cows and sheep, or disable it completely.\n*Sheep need to be added by CACO-compatible mods.
$CACODesc_HarvestBodyMsgBox	By default, blood and organs are automatically harvested whenever you activate a body, assuming you have the appropriate gear equipped and meet any other requirements.  You may instead choose to have a Message Box appear when you activate a body, allowing you to select what actions you'd like to perform.
$CACODesc_BombNotifications	Enables notification messages whenever you throw bombs to help you keep track of the remaining number of equipped bombs.
$CACODesc_LoadScreens	Enables new load screens with CACO-specific tips and information.
$CACODesc_DrunkAnimations	Enables drunken animations during certain stages of inebriation.
$CACODesc_DrunkVisuals	Enables blurred visual effects during certain stages of inebriation.
$CACODesc_DrunkMessages	Enables notification messages to help track your inebriation points.
$CACODesc_DrunkTolerance	This value controls how quickly you develop a tolerance to alcohol.  A setting of 5 means that you will need to get drunk 5 times to increase your tolerance level (getting drunk is defined as reaching Inebriation stage 4 or higher).   Change this setting to increase or decrease the number of times you need to get drunk to increase your tolerance level.
$CACODesc_WaterWellEnable	If selected, then you will be able to  acquire water from wells.
$CACODesc_WaterWellBucket	If selected, then you will be required to have a bucket in your inventory in order to get water from wells.
$CACODesc_CookingXPEnabled	Enabling this option will allow Cooking to be treated as a skill. XP will be accumulated whenever you create food items at a cookpot and will contribute to leveling your Cooking skill. This option will also enable minimum Skill level conditions on cooking recipes. This option can be disabled temporarily without losing your current skill level.
$CACODesc_CurrentCookingSkill	This is your current Cooking skill level.  Apprentice level recipes can be created once you reach level 25.  Adept level recipes can be created once you reach level 50.  Expert level recipes can be created once you reach level 75, and Master level recipes can be created once you reach level 100.
$CACODesc_AlchemyXPRate	Use this multiplier to increase or decrease the rate at which you gain Alchemy experience.  Values above 1 will cause you to level faster, and values below 1 will cause you to level more slowly.  Setting this option to 0 will prevent you from gaining any experience in Alchemy.
$CACODesc_CookingXPMult	Base Cooking XP for each item created is equal to the gold value of the item multiplied by this amount.  Increase this number if you wish to level faster, or decrease it if you wish to level more slowly.
$CACODesc_BasicNeedsHunger	Enables an extremely light-weight hunger penalty that uses almost no scripts.  There are three stages of Hunger, which will progressively decrease your health, stamina, and magicka regeneration.
$CACODesc_BasicNeedsFatigue	Enables an extremely light-weight sleep penalty that uses almost no scripts.  There are three stages of Fatigue, which will progressively decrease your skill XP rate, intelligence, and strength.
$CACODesc_SleepChanges	By default, CACO restricts the duration of the Rested, Well-Rested, and Lover's Comfort bonuses to equal the length of time slept, with a max of 8 hours.  Disabling this option will revert the Rested, Well-Rested, and Lover's Comfort bonuses to their static 8 hour duration.  However, it will also reduce or even eliminate the sleep bonuses granted by certain teas, salves, or other items added by CACO.  This feature must be enabled if you wish to use the optional Fatigue penalties.
$CACODesc_SleepAllowWerewolf	By default, the vanilla game does not allow werewolves to benefit from the Rested bonuses when they sleep.  This option simply removes that restriction so werewolves can get a good night's sleep and also benefit from their spouse's love and comfort.
$CACODesc_SleepMinHours	This is the minimum number of consecutive hours of sleep required to feel well-rested.  In addition, if you meet the requirements for Well-Rested or Lover's Comfort, but fall  up to two hours short of this minimum number, you'll receive the Rested bonus instead.
$CACODesc_CraftFreeWater	Certain cooking recipes require the use of water.  Enabling this option allows you to create water directly at the cookpot.  This option is intended for players who are not using a compatible 'needs' mod and don't want to bother gathering water from wells.
$CACODesc_CookingNewRecipes	This will enable all of the new cooking recipes  added by this mod and allow them to be available at the cookpot and oven if the correct conditions are met.  If you aren't interested in the new recipes and wish to disable them, then simply deselect this option.
$CACODesc_CookingInventoryCond	By default, cooking recipes will only show up in your crafting menu if you have one of the recipe's primary ingredients.  If you wish to see all available recipes, regardless of whether or not you have the correct ingredients, then simply deselect this option.
$CACODesc_AlchemyInventoryCond	By default, alchemy recipes will only show up in the Retort's crafting menu if you have one of the recipe's primary ingredients.  If you wish to see all available recipes, regardless of whether or not you have the correct ingredients, then simply deselect this option.
$CACODesc_RecipesTeachEffects	Automatically learn the ingredient properties mentioned in any alchemy book or recipe you read.
$CACODesc_HarvestFlesh	By default, once you have completed Namira's quest you will be able to harvest Flesh from dead NPCs by activating the body with a dagger or scalpel equipped. Changing this option to 'Always Allow' will remove this quest requirement, allowing you to harvest Flesh from any dead NPCs when you have a dagger or scalpel equipped.  You may also choose to disable this feature completely.
$CACODesc_MarkAsEaten	This will mark a dead body as 'eaten' after harvesting either Flesh or Blood.  Enabling this option may help prevent conflicts with certain mods that allow you to directly feed off of dead bodies.\nNOTE: Enabling this option will prevent you from harvesting BOTH Flesh and Blood from the same NPC.  Also, the order in which you harvest items will matter.  If you have the Anatomist perk, then make sure to use a scalpel to first harvest any organs.  Organs cannot be acquired from a body after Blood or Flesh has been harvested.
$CACODesc_CombinePortions	CACO automatically divides certain items like salt, flour, and wine into more logical cooking portions.  If you are using a mod that requires the original vanilla item as a cooking ingredient, then enabling this option will allow you to craft the original item for use in those recipes.
$CACODesc_DisableWorkbench	This will disable the changes made to the Alchemy workbench activation.  If enabled, you will no longer be able to use the Retort by activating the Alchemy lab, though the portable Retort can still be used from your inventory.  However, if you find that the Alchemy messagebox is conflicting with features from other mods, you can disable it here.
$CACODesc_DisableChurn	This will disable the changes CACO makes to the Hearthfire Butter Churn.  If you find that this change is conflicting with features from another mod, you can disable it here.
$CACODesc_DistillRecipes	One of the features granted by the Chymist perk is the ability to use a Retort to distill weaker potions into stronger versions.  If you don't want to see these recipes, or simply want to temporarily disable them, deselecting this option will hide them from the Retort's crafting menu.
$CACODesc_CookingRankNovice	You are currently a Novice Cook.  You can create basic recipes.
$CACODesc_CookingRankApprentice	You are currently an Apprentice Cook.  You can create Apprentice-level recipes.  Food effects are 25% stronger.
$CACODesc_CookingRankAdept	You are currently an Adept Chef.  You can create Adept-level recipes.  Food effects are 50% stronger.
$CACODesc_CookingRankExpert	You are  an Expert Chef and Food Connoisseur.  You can create Expert-level recipes.  Food effects are 75% stronger.
$CACODesc_CookingRankMaster	You are  a Master Gourmand.  You can create Master-level recipes.  Food effects are 100% stronger.
$CACODesc_NeedsNotifications	Enables notification messages when you transistion from one stage of hunger or fatigue to the next stage.
$CACODesc_XPNotifications	Enables notification messages when you gain cooking experience.
$CACODesc_PotionWeights	This will force player-made potions to update their weight.  Potions should be updated automatically when the game loads.  This option merely serves as a backup method.
$CACODesc_StopAnimations	This will forcibly stop the drunken animations on the player.  Animations should stop when the player is no longer drunk. However, certain actions may interfere with this feature and prevent the script function from triggering properly.  This option can be used as a backup if the drunken animations do not stop with the other inebriation effects.
$CACODesc_UpdateiNeedLists	This will repopulate iNeed's food and drink lists with items from CACO.  This should happen automatically when you install both mods, but if you feel there are items that are not being recognized properly by iNeed, then this option serves as a backup method.
$CACODesc_RagdollParalysis	Enabling this option will change the stiff paralysis effect to a more natural-looking ragdoll effect.  However, some people have reported that this causes the camera to get stuck in 3rd person mode.  This doesn't happen to everyone, but if you experience an issue with the ragdoll paralysis effect, try disabling this setting.